Sean Kim

Director of Finance

Address San Jose, CA, 95125

E-mail sean.m.kim.work@gmail.com

LinkedIn https://www.linkedin.com/in/seanmkim/

Aspiring Software Engineer with 10 years of work experience. Background as a Business Consultant, Director of Finance, and Youth Pastor to hundreds of students. Obsessive over the details and successful in consistently delivering results, always while working with an empathic and collaborative spirit. Never satisfied with the bare minimum, always wants to make a positive impact.

Skills

JavaScript	
HTML	
CSS	
SQL	
Excel	

Work History

2019-02 - Current

Director of Finance

Westgate Church, San Jose, CA

- Managed finance team to ensure accuracy and timeliness in day-to-day operations and communication in church of over 3000 members.
- Analyzed budget plans and costs to forecast trends and recommend changes across 60 different departments.
- Produced key dashboards and reports outlining financial data to assist executive leadership with making strategic plans and operational decisions.
- Implemented process improvements of key financial processes, significantly cutting time spent on month end close, annual budget creation, and audit preparation while increasing accuracy.

2017-08 - 2018-12

Youth Pastor

New Life Vision Church, Los Angeles, CA

- Managed and trained team of 20 volunteers to mentor and empathetically counsel 100+ students, while fostering team morale and well-being.
- Brainstormed, wrote, and publicly delivered 30 minute sermon to 100+ students on weekly basis.
- Strategized and executed end-to-end logistics for biannual youth conferences.

2017-04 - 2018-09 Enrollment Management Research Associate

Biola University, La Mirada, CA

- Developed data visualization dashboards that provided key enrollment data to university top leadership, which influenced admissions marketing and budgeting decisions and led to adoption of Tableau across organization.
- Distilled large amounts of data and produced reports and documents outlining key details, which was instrumental in qualifying Biola for NCAA Division II.
- Developed complex Excel macros and Google Sheets scripts and was recognized as subject matter expert on spreadsheets.

2015-11 - 2017-07 Youth Pastor

Vision Community Church, Anaheim, CA

- Provided spiritual and administrative leadership to church, including managing volunteer operations, developing and administering annual budget, and leading worship services.
- Taught, mentored, and counseled over 50 youth and college students to promote positive self-esteem and be influential members of their communities.

2013-10 - 2015-08 Business Analyst

Anritsu Corporation, Morgan Hill, CA

- Delivered essential business insights for executives by developing Excel dashboards with complex macros, which led to cost savings over \$300,000 and increased production efficiencies.
- Recognized as subject matter expert for spreadsheets across organization.
- Conducted interviews with key business users to collect information on business processes and user requirements.

2010-08 - 2012-11 Business Transformation Consultant

IBM, San Francisco, CA

- Managed collaboration between developers, business users, and project executives of Fortune 500 semiconductor company to develop and test functionalities of custom finance reporting system.
- Forecasted and regularly presented project progress to clients.
- Designed SQL queries to collect and analyze large data sets and test system functionality.
- Created detailed documentation on business processes and reporting system functional specifications.

Education

2020-10 - Current Coding Bootcamp: Full Stack Web Development

Rithm School - San Francisco, CA

2015-08 - Current Master of Divinity: Pastoral and General Ministries

Biola University - La Mirada, CA

• GPA: 3.95

2006-01 - 2010-06

B.S: Industrial Engineering & Management Sciences

Northwestern University - Evanston, IL

- Minored in Economics
- GPA: 3.51